O. RICHARD DAMILOLA

WEBSITE DEVELOPER

CAREER OBJECTIVE

To obtain a responsible and challenging Front End Developer's position where my education and work experience will have valuable application. A web developer with 3+ years of experience in front-end web development, branding, graphics design and business growth across music, technology, media, and entertainment industries.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

January 2021–Present | JTI Space, Lagos, Nigeria Front-end Web Developer

- Produced websites compatible with multiple browsers.
- Managed full-cycle design tasks, handling phases from conception to completion while maintaining guidelines throughout.
- Completed full redesigns of existing websites to improve navigation, enhance visuals and strengthen search engine rankings.
- Developed designs to meet specific requirements such as quick-loading sites with particular layouts.

February 2022–March 2022 | Simdbuzz ICT Capacity Hub, Ilorin, Nigeria

Instructor

- Trained over 35+ students on using Microsoft Office Package and WordPress website design.
- Developed classroom guidelines and assignment rules to communicate expectations.
- Applied various teaching aids to minimize learning gaps and instruct and motivate students.
- Evaluated and revised lesson plans and course content to achieve student-centered learning.

June 2018–August 2021 | Easy Company Reg, Lagos, Nigeria

Freelance Web Designer/Graphics Designer

- Quickly learned new skills and applied them to daily tasks, improving efficiency and productivity.
- Exceeded goals through effective task prioritization and great work ethic.

(+234) 70 2512 7767

ogungbilerichard@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/richdam

EDUCATION

October 2021

Kwara State Polytechnic, Kwara State, Nigeria HND, Computer Science,

Honors: HND (GPA: 2.7/4.0)

RELEVANT SKILLS

HTML & CSS

JavaScript

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

Wordpress Design

CorelDraw

Little PHP

Wondershare Filmora

Microsoft Office

Code Debugging

UI Improvement

Project Estimation

May 2018-October 2019 | Rank Infinite Ltd, Lagos, Nigeria

WordPress Developer

- Delivered quality commercial websites that met coding standards and cross-browser compatibilities.
- Collaborated with design and project developers to understand project scope and offer elegant, creative and scalable solutions.
- Designed and implemented website from initial concept, site architecture and wire frames to finished deliverable.
- Created and updated re-usable code libraries to streamline WordPress development cycle.
- Leveraged strong understanding of WordPress core to manipulate admin and theme components.

September 2017–April 2018 | I. J. Ukwetang & Associates, Lagos, Nigeria

Secretary/IT Personnel

- Scanned documents and saved in database to keep records of essential organizational information.
- Drafted reports for upper management as directed.
- Managed documents by organizing forms, making photocopies, filing records, preparing correspondence and creating reports.
- Scrubbed data for errors and made corrections to maintain clean records.

Requirements Gathering

Agile Workflow

Video File Editing

WavePad Sound Editor

Maintenance and Repair

Flexible & Adaptable